# **ALEXIA BERNARDO**

Email: me@alexiabernardo.com Phone: (845) 240 3990

Website: alexiabernardo.com LinkedIn: alexiabernardo GitHub: abernardo97

Software Developer in Test with 2 years of experience building test automation suites for digital products companies in the web and mobile sector. Implemented and built software in full software development lifecycle in cross-functional agile scrum teams.

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Working in Cross-Functional Agile Teams (Scrum)
- Building Test Automation Suites (XCUI, Cypress)
- Developing Test Strategies and Plans (Jira, Zephyr)
- Executing Unit/UI Tests in CI/CD (Azure DevOps)
- Object-Oriented Programming (C#, Swift, TypeScript)
- Writing and Preparing Technical Documentation

# **EMPLOYMENT**

# Software Test Engineer @ WillowTree Inc.

Jul 2019 - Present

A digital product agency founded in 2008, with over 500 employees that has driven growth for world leading brands from mobile apps to responsive websites.

- **Building Test Automation Suites (XCUI, Swift):** Refactored existing XCUI test suite for an existing client project, by adopting a Page Object design pattern to allow for executing UI tests in Azure DevOps.
- Working in Cross-Functional Agile Teams: Captures key learning growth opportunities, by collaborating with teammates on priority issues and document the best approach considering the current project ecosystem.
- **Developing Test Strategies and Plans:** Developed a process improvement for triaging critical feedback from the client to the development team during user acceptance testing, to reduce loss of production time.
- **Preparing Technical Documentation:** Curated a learning pathway viewed company wide, to contribute growth in learning how people with disabilities use technology to build digital accessible and inclusive product design.

## Interactive Developer Intern @ American Greetings

Jan 2018 - Aug 2018

A greeting products manufacturer founded in 1906, that is committed to making the world a thoughtful and caring place through engaging and imaginative products.

- **Object-Oriented Programming (TypeScript):** Increased ecard membership sales (top 10 cards), jump starting hidden object game ecard product line by programming 2D special effect animations on ecards and reducing loading times by 40% by compressing game assets in a sprite atlas.
- **Developed Strategies:** Pitched a potential business venture to management in a team, winning 1st Place, by creating a prototype during Intern Hackday that expands a current product line by combining physical greeting cards with AR.

## **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science Game Design and Development**, Minor in Japanese, Rochester Institute of Technology **Hackathon Awards**: Best Mash-Up of the Wegmans API, AGI Intern Hackday 1st Place, Best Teaching Programming Hack **Certifications**: Professional Scrum Master I (PSM I) Certification

#### **VOLUNTEERISM**

Director @ Tora-Con Apr 2018 - May 2019

A anime convention founded in 2004, with over 70 staff and 150 volunteers that has held a celebration of anime, cosplay, and Japanese culture through games, panels, contests.

- **Worked in Cross-Functional Teams:** Directed 12+ staff to drive business to accumulate funding for the operating costs of hosting a convention through ~3450 tickets sales from vendors, artists alley, and general registration.
- **Prepared Documentation:** Delivered training sessions for 70+ staff, by creating a 30 minute presentation talk in giving a positive first impression, training customer service skills, and giving advice on staying calm under pressure.

## Coordinator @ Tora-Con

Aug 2015 - Apr 2018

- **Worked in Cross-Functional Teams:** Directed a team of 35+ volunteers by managing to distribute ~3300 physical tickets on the registration tables and service desk area during the day of the convention by serving guests.
- **Developed Strategies:** Created training materials for 150+ volunteers, by creating presentation slides and cheat sheets distributed to the volunteers prior to the convention.